<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wilderness Prime</title>
    <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wilderness Prime</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.wildernessprime.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperlite Mountain Gear Ultamid 4</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/reviews/hgm-ultamid-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/reviews/hgm-ultamid-4/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation/</guid>
      <description>Navigation is critical for any expedition, and especially those venturing into remote areas where the trail network is more tenuous. You&amp;rsquo;ll realise I&amp;rsquo;m a great believer in technology - however I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out from the outset that a paper map backup is always required.
In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through some of the preparation I&amp;rsquo;m doing for navigating the 1700km GHT. This trail posed my biggest challenge to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 5: La Fouly, Courmayeur</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-5-la-fouly-courmayeur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-5-la-fouly-courmayeur/</guid>
      <description>Onwards and upwards into the foothills of Mont Blanc from Lac Champex towards Italy. La Fouly is a cute little town with an amazing view, and I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend staying at the excellent Maya Joie hostel.
As we climbed further into the hills, the buildings became less frequent and the landscape more barren. The view down the valley towards Courmayeur from the Swiss Itallian border was one of the best of the trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 4: Verbier, Champex</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-4-verbier-champex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-4-verbier-champex/</guid>
      <description>Arguably the most beautiful town in the European Alps, Verbier overlooks the most picturesque valley. After the last few days of rocks, scrambling and mountains, this all seems rather civilised.
After a day hiking along the valley floor, again I&amp;rsquo;m ascending into the hills towards Lac Champex.
Again this doesn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Dix, Prafleuri</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-3-dix-prafleuri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 16:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-3-dix-prafleuri/</guid>
      <description>The next section led deep into the mountains. Up the valley to the ski resort of Arolla, and over the Pas de Chèvres to the imposing view of the Mont Blanc de Cheilon with La Cabane des Dix overlooking. I&amp;rsquo;ve visited the Dix hut several times on the winter version of this route, so I pushed on towards the Pas du Chat and the Lac Dix beyond.
Cabane de Prafleuri isn&amp;rsquo;t in the most picturesque setting - crouching in the barren quarry carved out of the landscape during the construction of the Dix dam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Moiry</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-2-tbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-2-tbc/</guid>
      <description>The hike over the mountains to Gruben was a long way, but well worth the effort. The next day came a long traverse past the Lac de Moiry and up to the snout of the Moiry Glacier
The glacier was spectacular, and the cabin was the most amazing place, perched on the side of the mountain overlooking the river of ice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Zermatt</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/summer-haute-route-tour-du-mont-blanc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/summer-haute-route-tour-du-mont-blanc/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Haute Route in the opposite direction to most people, starting in Zermatt under the majestic Matterhorn and heading down the valley towards Grächen along the Europaweg trail.
The Charles Kuonen Suspension Bridge is the longest in the world, spanning almost 500m (1620ft). A recent landslide blocked the trail shortly after the bridge, forcing a re-route down into the valley to Randa.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>