<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wilderness Prime</title>
    <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wilderness Prime</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.wildernessprime.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - Flashcards</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>Robin&amp;rsquo;s guide book is excellent, but not organised optimally for a thru-hike of the GHT. I created a set of flashcards, one for each day of our itinerary. They are intended to be printed on A5, double sided. Included in each page is:
 The description from Robin&amp;rsquo;s guide book. Additional description from Himalaya Adventure Labs (marked with HAL). A crop from the Himalaya Map House 1:150k raster map. Stats from the GPX route including elevation range, min, max, total ascent and descent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - GPX routes</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-gpx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-gpx/</guid>
      <description>ViewRanger will provide topo maps of the entire trekking area, but these would be of limited use without the route highlighted. The GHT is infrequently trekked, so there&amp;rsquo;s relatively few digital resources available. For the more popular ares, the ViewRanger topo maps often include footpaths - but for much of the trek there is nothing plotted on the map.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to bring all the available GPX resources together in this section:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-methods/</guid>
      <description>Navigating with the aid of digital topo maps is a game changer for unsupported trekking. However, extreme care must be taken because digital devices often fail in the field. We will be using several backups to mitigate this:
 My iPhone with topo mapping, offline maps and GPX route. Mathilde&amp;rsquo;s phone with similar setup. Backup iPod touch with similar setup. Garmin Fenix 5 GPS watch with waypoints and analogue compass (see Emergency Navigation article).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Itinerary - Resupply</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/itinerary-resupply/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/itinerary-resupply/</guid>
      <description>Our general food strategy is to eat freshly cooked local food wherever possible, and not to reply on buying unprepared food along the trail that we cook later. Remote villages often will have nothing to sell apart from perhaps rice, flour and lentils - not exactly calorie dense or backpacking stove compatible. In order to ensure we have enough food between resupply points, I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to estimate where we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to eat local food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Itinerary - Summary</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/itinerary-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/itinerary-summary/</guid>
      <description>In any trek it&amp;rsquo;s important to get an idea of the approximate itinerary. Of course, on a long trek like this the exact route will need to be flexible, but I&amp;rsquo;ll plan the intended route and the maps and guide book will provide alternates when we need them. The alternates are almost certainly going to take us south and down hill where services and accommodation are more usually more plentiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - Sources</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-sources/</guid>
      <description>Navigation is critical for any expedition, and especially those venturing into remote areas where the trail network is more tenuous. You&amp;rsquo;ll realise I&amp;rsquo;m a great believer in technology - however I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out from the outset that a paper map backup is always required.
In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through some of the sources that are available for navigating the the 1300km Great Himalaya Trail. This posed my biggest navigation challenge to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Great Himalaya Trail?</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/what-is-the-great-himalaya-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/what-is-the-great-himalaya-trail/</guid>
      <description>The Great Himalaya Trail is the combination of several trail networks stretching the length of the Himalaya range, with sections in India, Nepal, Bhutan and Tibet. Our trek will follow the High Route of the Nepal section from Kanchenjunga on the Indian border in the East to Hilsa on the Chinese border in the West.
The concept of the high route is that it follows the highest feasible continuous route across the country, averaging 3,750m (12,000ft) of elevation, with several passes taking us over 6,100m (20,000ft).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 5: La Fouly, Courmayeur</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-5-la-fouly-courmayeur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-5-la-fouly-courmayeur/</guid>
      <description>Onwards and upwards into the foothills of Mont Blanc from Lac Champex towards Italy. La Fouly is a cute little town with an amazing view, and I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend staying at the excellent Maya Joie hostel.
As we climbed further into the hills, the buildings became less frequent and the landscape more barren. The view down the valley towards Courmayeur from the Swiss Itallian border was one of the best of the trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 4: Verbier, Champex</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-4-verbier-champex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-4-verbier-champex/</guid>
      <description>Arguably the most beautiful town in the European Alps, Verbier overlooks the most picturesque valley. After the last few days of rocks, scrambling and mountains, this all seems rather civilised.
After a day hiking along the valley floor, again I&amp;rsquo;m ascending into the hills towards Lac Champex.
Again this doesn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Dix, Prafleuri</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-3-dix-prafleuri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 16:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-3-dix-prafleuri/</guid>
      <description>The next section led deep into the mountains. Up the valley to the ski resort of Arolla, and over the Pas de Chèvres to the imposing view of the Mont Blanc de Cheilon with La Cabane des Dix overlooking. I&amp;rsquo;ve visited the Dix hut several times on the winter version of this route, so I pushed on towards the Pas du Chat and the Lac Dix beyond.
Cabane de Prafleuri isn&amp;rsquo;t in the most picturesque setting - crouching in the barren quarry carved out of the landscape during the construction of the Dix dam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Moiry</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-2-moiry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-2-moiry/</guid>
      <description>The hike over the mountains to Gruben was a long way, but well worth the effort. The next day came a long traverse past the Lac de Moiry and up to the snout of the Moiry Glacier
The glacier was spectacular, and the cabin was the most amazing place, perched on the side of the mountain overlooking the river of ice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Zermatt</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-1-zermatt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/summer-haute-route-2018/part-1-zermatt/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Haute Route in the opposite direction to most people, starting in Zermatt under the majestic Matterhorn and heading down the valley towards Grächen along the Europaweg trail.
The Charles Kuonen Suspension Bridge is the longest in the world, spanning almost 500m (1620ft). A recent landslide blocked the trail shortly after the bridge, forcing a re-route down into the valley to Randa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperlite Mountain Gear Ultamid 4</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/reviews/hgm-ultamid-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/reviews/hgm-ultamid-4/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/authors/dave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/authors/dave/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/authors/mathilde/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/authors/mathilde/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>