<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Annapurna Circuit on Wilderness Prime</title>
    <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Annapurna Circuit on Wilderness Prime</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17: Tatopani to Ghorepani</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-17-ghorepani/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-17-ghorepani/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   The trek from Tatopani to Ghorepani is probably the easiest to navigate. There are signs pointing to Ghorepani at every single intersection and the path is usually made from hand laid stones, making it the obvious route to take.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16: Ghasa to Tatopani</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-16-tatopani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-16-tatopani/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   As said in the previous paragraph, we made the bright decision to do two days of trekking in one. We were still in good spirits when leaving Ghasa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 15: Larjung to Ghasa</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-15-ghasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-15-ghasa/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   The day starts off on the road, but our GPS directs us across a footpath on the river. After getting halfway across the large expanse, we realize we are unable to pass and have to walk all the way back and around on the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 14: Marpha to Larjung</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-14-larjung/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-14-larjung/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   I recommend leaving Marpha at 7:00am to avoid the intense afternoon winds. After walking through town, you can cross over the bridge to get off the main road and onto the trekking trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 13: Kagbeni to Marpha</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-13-marpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-13-marpha/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   We originally planned to walk to Jomsom, but upon arriving, opted to keep moving on to Marpha. The road from Kagbeni to Jomsom is a dusty construction zone mess that crosses an empty river bed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 12: Muktinath to Kagbeni</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-12-kagbeni/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-12-kagbeni/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   A friend of mine told me Kagbeni was a beautiful “sleepy town” that I should definitely go see. Most of the trekking route has been catered to tourism, and I was curious to see a town that hadn’t been completely formed around the tourist trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 11: Thorung Phedi to Muktinath</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-11-muktinath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-11-muktinath/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   We pre ordered our breakfast the night before which included honey porridge at 4:00am and two hard boiled eggs to go. After packing and getting dressed, we ended up starting the hike at 5:00am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10: Yak Kharka to Thorung Phedi</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-10-thorung-phedi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-10-thorung-phedi/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   Yak Kharka literally means yak shed, so you’ll see a ton of yaks being herded to the fields beyond the town. On the way to Ledar we passed all the herders heading out in the morning in what felt like the most authentic part of the trek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9: Manang to Yak Kharka</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-9-yak-kharka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-9-yak-kharka/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   To leave Manang, you’ll need to pass an ACAP check post to show your permits. After that, follow the main path and the signs pointing to Thorung La until you are out of the village.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8: Braka to Manang</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-8-manang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-8-manang/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   We spent a day in Braka to acclimate. The best way to acclimate is to walk high and sleep low. There are two popular side treks that start in Braka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7: Upper Pisang to Braka</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-7-braka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-7-braka/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   Our guesthouse owner directed us toward the path to Manang. It starts out nice and gentle with beautiful views of the mountains to the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6: Chame to Upper Pisang</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-6-pisang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-6-pisang/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   After leaving Chame, we followed the main road for about an hour and a half. Along the way we stumbled upon an apple farm with a small tea shop and an extravagant hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5: Dharapani to Chame</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-5-chame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-5-chame/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   The day starts out back on the main road with a nice gradual incline. There’s a fork in the road, and we took the one going to the right which goes over a bridge to the other side of the river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4: Chamje to Dharapani</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-4-dharapani/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-4-dharapani/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   This is the first day completely off the main road. The walk to Tal is mostly uphill and some sections are a bit steep, making it a long morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: Bahundana to Chamje</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-3-chamje/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-3-chamje/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   The trek from Bahundana to Chamje starts off rather easy. There are some markers on the road to follow some side trails, but they lead out of the way and straight uphill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Bhulbhule to Bahundanda</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-2-bahundanda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-2-bahundanda/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   The walk from Bhulbhule to Bahundanda takes about five hours. We got a late start due to rain in the morning, so we didn’t set out until 10:30am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1: Besi Sahar to Bhulbhule</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-1-bhulbhule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/annapurna-circuit/day-1-bhulbhule/</guid>
      <description>I hiked the Annapurna Circuit with Michelle from Full Time Explorer. She did a great write-up of our trek which she kindly let me borrow, so what you see below is Michelle&#39;s text and my photos. You can find her original article at Annapurna Circuit Itinerary.   The tourist buses from Kathmandu to Besi Sahar weren’t running when I went, so I took the local bus. It takes between 6 and 10 hours depending on your luck.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>