<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Great Himalaya Trail on Wilderness Prime</title>
    <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Great Himalaya Trail on Wilderness Prime</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/tracking/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re planning to start the hike around April 12th 2019. Our Garmin InReach satellite tracker will update this map every few minutes. Our intended route is marked in red and yellow - each coloured section being one day of hiking, and our actual track is blue. You can send us a short message by clicking the Message button in the left panel.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Models</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/models/</guid>
      <description>Maps3d.io is an amazing service that easily converts a GPX route into a GLTF format 3D model, using satellite imagery and elevation data. These can be displayed on the web (as below) or in a mobile app.
I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded models for all 115 days to my phone, so while we&amp;rsquo;re on the trek we should be able to preview the next section in glorious 3D. It makes visualising the route so much easier than looking at a topo map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tilamn&#39;s Pass</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/tilmans-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/tilmans-pass/</guid>
      <description>   5,308m, D061 - Navigation on the approach to Tilman&amp;rsquo;s is reportedly rather difficult. It&amp;rsquo;s less technical than the other passes and lower elevation at just 5,308m. A steep scramble beside an icefall is followed by an crevassed plateau, then a steep scramble down. The exit is a long walk along a glacier with a tricky river crossing at the end.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tashi Labsta La</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/tashi-labsta-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/tashi-labsta-la/</guid>
      <description>   5,760m, D043 - The route over Tashi Labsta La is a rocky scramble with constant danger from rockfall and crevasses. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to be very careful on this section, but it&amp;rsquo;s perhaps less technical than the previous three passes.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amphu Labsta La</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/amphu-labsta-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/amphu-labsta-la/</guid>
      <description>   5,845m, D031 - Amphu Labsta La is reportedly one of the most dangerous passes in Nepal, and certainly the most technical point on our trek. Climbing a steep icefall will require full climbing safety gear, and the descent is just as tricky with a 30m rappel.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Col</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/west-col/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/west-col/</guid>
      <description>   6,190m, D029 - The top of West Col is the highest point on the trek at 6,190m, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve much climbing from the plateau. However a 200m rappel awaits on the other side. I&amp;rsquo;ve read disconcerting reports about the state of the fixed ropes on this section, so extreme care will have to be taken.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sherpani Col</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/sherpani-col/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/sherpani-col/</guid>
      <description>6,180m, D028 - Sherpani &amp;amp; West Col are two impressive passes connected by a glaciated plateau. The ascent of Sherpani is a tough scramble followed by some easy rock climbing, followed by a 35m rappel down to the plateau. Rockfall from above and crevasses will be a constant danger.
The guidebook and most of the itineraries I&amp;rsquo;ve found recommend spending the night on the plateau between the two passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountaineering</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/mountaineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/mountaineering/</guid>
      <description>The route has five passes that require moderate mountaineering skills and equipment. You can read more about the gear we&amp;rsquo;ll be using on these sections on the Gear - Mountaineering page.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be enlisting the services of a mountaineering guide to assist us over these five sections - Sherpani Col, West Col, Amphu Labsta La, Tashi Labsta La and Tilman&amp;rsquo;s Pass.
Our mountaineering guide, Zangmu Sherpa is from the Everest Makalu area has provided assistance in 8000m+ mountain climbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trash</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/trash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/trash/</guid>
      <description>As our backpacking food arrived I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting more and more concerned about the amount of plastic trash we&amp;rsquo;ll be generating. The remote regions of Nepal have very limited rubbish disposal facilities, and plastic trash is often dumped. I was constantly depressed by the trash littering the trails when I hiked the Annapurna Circuit last year. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to make a pledge.
Our pledge We won&amp;rsquo;t leave any plastic trash in Nepal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/communication/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll be using a Garmin InReach Mini for communicating with the outside world during the trek. It uses the Iridium satellite network to allow two-way short message communication anywhere in the world, even when far away from a mobile network. It has several useful features:
Messaging The device can send and receive short, 140 character messages. Messages are sent from the outside world using a simple web form - feel free to send us a message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/temperatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/temperatures/</guid>
      <description> It&amp;rsquo;s possible to work out the approximate temperatures on the trail by taking the average monthly temperatures in Kathmandu at 1,400m, and using the adiabatic lapse rate of 9.8C per km. This gives us a very approximate estimate of the temperature we&amp;rsquo;ll be experiencing on the trail.
The results show we&amp;rsquo;ll be expecting a rather chilly -20C on some nights, but daytime temperatures rarely dip below freezing.
Maximum daytime temperature Minimum overnight temperature Average temperatures in Kathmandu Overnight low (C)Daytime high (C) Apr1228 May1529 Jun1729 Jul1827 Aug1827 Sep1727   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsors - RxBars</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/sponsors-rxbars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/sponsors-rxbars/</guid>
      <description>Thanks very much to RxBar for sending us a selection of their RxBar energy bars. They&amp;rsquo;ll make a great calorie dense breakfast, and made from real food ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsors - Expedition Foods</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/sponsors-expedition-foods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/sponsors-expedition-foods/</guid>
      <description>Thanks very much to Expeditions Foods for offering us a generous discount on their 1,000 calorie Extreme Energy dehydrated meals. They&amp;rsquo;re high calorie, energy dense meals perfect for a big expedition like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsors - FBOMB</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/sponsors-fbomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/sponsors-fbomb/</guid>
      <description>Thanks very much to FBOMB for sending us some of their Premium Oils and Nut Butter sachets. We&amp;rsquo;ll be adding oil to our evening meals to give us a calorie boost, and the nut butter will make a great snack during the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear - Clothes</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-clothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-clothes/</guid>
      <description>Clothes I&amp;rsquo;ll take a single change of underwear and long-sleeve t-shirt - both Icebreaker merino wool. I&amp;rsquo;ll take a pair of Darn Tough socks for the warmer sections and a warmer pair of Smartwool socks for the cold sections. The boots I&amp;rsquo;ll be using aren&amp;rsquo;t particularly warm so I&amp;rsquo;ll need the extra insulation.
When it gets cold I&amp;rsquo;ll be slipping into my Patagonia Capilene Air thermal layer, which is incredibly light for the warmth it provides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear - Miscellaneous</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-miscellaneous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-miscellaneous/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll be taking a Suntactics S5-Lite solar panel, and an Anker 13,000 mAh power bank. This is rather an unknown for me - I&amp;rsquo;ve never done a trek that relied on solar charging before. During the Annapurna Circuit last year, it was quite common to have power provided in the tea houses, but I&amp;rsquo;ve heard this isn&amp;rsquo;t the case for much of the country. I&amp;rsquo;d like to be as self-sufficient as possible so the solar panel is a necessity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear - Mountaineering</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-mountaineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-mountaineering/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the lightest mountaineering gear available. Although we&amp;rsquo;ll only be using it for five days, we&amp;rsquo;ll be carrying it for several weeks of hiking, so weight is critical.
When choosing mountaineering gear, it&amp;rsquo;s worth setting expectations on the limitations. Lighter weight gear won&amp;rsquo;t be as capable as heavier. We&amp;rsquo;re expecting some steep snowy scrambles, rappels from fixed ropes, perhaps rappels with our own ropes from pre-existing anchors, and glacier travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear - Cooking</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-cooking/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to take a canister stove - we&amp;rsquo;ll be getting regular resupply packages that will replenish our gas supplies, so a heavy complex liquid fuel stove won&amp;rsquo;t be needed. However, we&amp;rsquo;re still confirming that it&amp;rsquo;ll be possible to get the gas canisters delivered to the last two resupply points in Ringmo and Gamgadhi. We were initially planning to send the resupply packages by internal flight from Kathmandu, but gas canisters aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed on any flights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear - Sleeping</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-sleeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-sleeping/</guid>
      <description>I had initially intended to use my Zpacks 20F (-7C) sleeping bags, augmented with down jacket and pants. However, after working out the overnight temperatures we&amp;rsquo;ll be facing (as low as -20C) I changed my mind and we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking my Feathered Friends Snowbunting 0F (-17C) sleeping bags. They&amp;rsquo;re not particularly lightweight at around 1.3kg, and don&amp;rsquo;t pack down very small. We&amp;rsquo;ll take both models to Nepal and possible swap to the lighter ones for the warmer sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear - Camping</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-camping/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll be sleeping in a Hyperlite Mountain Gear Ultamid 4, which is a extremely sturdy four-season pyramid tent made of ultra light DCF fabric. The outer tent is as basic as you can imagine - just a four-sided pyramid of single-layer DCF with nothing else. No floor, no inner tent, no bug protection. In the high mountains you don&amp;rsquo;t really need an inner tent - a lightweight plastic ground sheet will do just fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear - Pack</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-pack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/gear-pack/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be using the ZPacks Arc Blast. This is my third Arc Blast and without a doubt my favourite ever pack. The feather light 605g combined with the amazing load isolation is an unbeatable combination. However, for this trek it has proved difficult. It&amp;rsquo;s the main compartment of the pack is only 42L, and with 10 days of food, a winter sleeping bag, half the tent and some group gear it&amp;rsquo;s completely full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Map</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/interactive-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/interactive-map/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s an interactive map of the route. You can use the tabs at the bottom to zoom in to the detail of a single day.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/food/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/food/</guid>
      <description>We will eat as much freshly prepared food as we can. Dal Bhat is delicious and we want to support the local economy as much as possible. However, we&amp;rsquo;ll only have access to locally prepared food on about half the 115 days in the itinerary. The rest of the food we&amp;rsquo;ll have to take with us. We would love to be able to resupply at shops along the route, but the remote villages rarely sell backpacking compatible food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-apps/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;ve not yet found an app that has all the features I need for navigating a long trek like the Great Himalaya Trail, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be using these three apps in combination:
ViewRanger Advantages: Great maps. Ultimate flexibility - you can load lots of routes and adjust colours etc.
Disadvantages: Downloading maps takes hours. Impossible to select waypoints that are close to routes - e.g. most of them. (I think this bug is fixed in the Android version).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - Emergencies</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-emergencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-emergencies/</guid>
      <description>I carry a Garmin Fenix 5 GPS watch, which I use just for emergency navigation. Emergency navigation is for when there&amp;rsquo;s zero visibility, no trail and adverse weather. The times when you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be taking your phone out of your pocket every two minutes to check where you are.
I leave the watch turned off, but easily accessible in an outside pocket so I can get it when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - Flashcards</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>Robin&amp;rsquo;s guide book is excellent, but not organised optimally for a thru-hike of the GHT. I created a set of flashcards, one for each day of our itinerary. They are intended to be printed on A5, double sided. Included in each page is:
 The description from Robin&amp;rsquo;s guide book. Additional description from Himalaya Adventure Labs (marked with HAL). A crop from the Himalaya Map House 1:150k raster map. Stats from the GPX route including elevation range, min, max, total ascent and descent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - GPS routes</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-gps/</guid>
      <description>ViewRanger will provide topo maps of the entire trekking area, but these would be of limited use without the route highlighted. The GHT is infrequently trekked, so there&amp;rsquo;s relatively few digital resources available. For the more popular ares, the ViewRanger topo maps often include footpaths - but for much of the trek there is nothing plotted on the map.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to bring all the available GPS resources together in this section:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-methods/</guid>
      <description>Navigating with the aid of digital topo maps is a game changer for unsupported trekking. However, extreme care must be taken because digital devices often fail in the field. We will be using several backups to mitigate this:
 My iPhone with topo mapping, offline maps and GPX route (see Navigation - Apps article). Mathilde&amp;rsquo;s phone with similar setup. Backup iPod touch with similar setup. Garmin Fenix 5 GPS watch with waypoints and analogue compass (see Navigation - Emergencies article).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Itinerary - Resupply</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/itinerary-resupply/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/itinerary-resupply/</guid>
      <description>Our general food strategy is to eat freshly cooked local food wherever possible, and not to reply on buying unprepared food along the trail that we cook later. Remote villages often will have nothing to sell apart from perhaps rice, flour and lentils - not exactly calorie dense or backpacking stove compatible. In order to ensure we have enough food between resupply points, I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to estimate where we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to eat local food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Itinerary - Summary</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/itinerary-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/itinerary-summary/</guid>
      <description>In any trek it&amp;rsquo;s important to get an idea of the approximate itinerary. Of course, on a long trek like this the exact route will need to be flexible, but I&amp;rsquo;ll plan the intended route and the maps and guide book will provide alternates when we need them. The alternates are almost certainly going to take us south and down hill where services and accommodation are more usually more plentiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation - Sources</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/navigation-sources/</guid>
      <description>Navigation is critical for any expedition, and especially those venturing into remote areas where the trail network is more tenuous. You&amp;rsquo;ll realise I&amp;rsquo;m a great believer in technology - however I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out from the outset that a paper map backup is always required.
In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through some of the sources that are available for navigating the the 1300km Great Himalaya Trail. This posed my biggest navigation challenge to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Great Himalaya Trail?</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/what-is-the-great-himalaya-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail/what-is-the-great-himalaya-trail/</guid>
      <description>The Great Himalaya Trail is the combination of several trail networks stretching the length of the Himalaya range, with sections in India, Nepal, Bhutan and Tibet. Our trek will follow the High Route of the Nepal section from Kanchenjunga on the Indian border in the East to Hilsa on the Chinese border in the West.
The concept of the high route is that it follows the highest feasible continuous route across the country, averaging 3,750m (12,000ft) of elevation, with several passes taking us over 6,100m (20,000ft).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>