<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Great Himalaya Trail 2019 on Wilderness Prime</title>
    <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Great Himalaya Trail 2019 on Wilderness Prime</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resupply locations</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/resupply/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/resupply/</guid>
      <description>Our general food strategy is to eat freshly cooked local food wherever possible, and not to reply on buying unprepared food along the trail that we cook later. Remote villages often will have nothing to sell apart from perhaps rice, flour and lentils - not exactly calorie dense or backpacking stove compatible. In order to ensure we have enough food between resupply points, I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to estimate where we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to eat local food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Itinerary</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/itinerary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/itinerary/</guid>
      <description>In any trek it&amp;rsquo;s important to get an idea of the approximate itinerary. Of course, on a long trek like this the exact route will need to be flexible, but I&amp;rsquo;ll plan the intended route and the maps and guide book will provide alternates when we need them. The alternates are almost certainly going to take us south and down hill where services and accommodation are more usually more plentiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation Sources</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/navigation-sources/</guid>
      <description>Navigation is critical for any expedition, and especially those venturing into remote areas where the trail network is more tenuous. You&amp;rsquo;ll realise I&amp;rsquo;m a great believer in technology - however I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out from the outset that a paper map backup is always required.
In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through some of the preparation I&amp;rsquo;m doing for navigating the 1700km GHT. This trail posed my biggest challenge to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Great Himalaya Trail?</title>
      <link>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/what-is-the-great-himalaya-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wildernessprime.com/expeditions/great-himalaya-trail-2019/what-is-the-great-himalaya-trail/</guid>
      <description>The Great Himalaya Trail is the combination of several trail networks stretching the length of the Himalaya range, with sections in India, Nepal, Bhutan and Tibet. Our trek will follow the High Route of the Nepal section from Kanchenjunga on the Indian border in the East to Hilsa on the Chinese border in the West.
The concept of the high route is that it follows the highest feasible continuous route across the country, averaging 3,750m (12,000ft) of elevation, with several passes taking us over 6,100m (20,000ft).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>